## Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai

madthanu@gmail.com 608 698 9678

I am interested in the area of computer systems, particularly in cross-layer optimization and reliability. I have a strong background on storage systems from my research. I also have experience building distributed databases, measuring performance and durability in databases, and high availability in clusters.

#### Work Experience

### Senior Software Engineer, Google Inc, Sunnyvale

(Sep 2019 - Current)

• Currently working on a high-performance distributed database.

# Software Engineer, Google Inc, Sunnyvale

(Dec 2016 - Sep 2019)

• Worked in the Cloud SQL team. Focused on improving performance and durability, and lead high availability in database clusters and better reliability infrastructure.

#### Research Assistant, Computer Science Dept., UW-Madison

(Spring 2010 - Dec 2016)

• Worked on storage performance and reliability with Prof. Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau and Prof. Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau.

### Software Engineering Intern, Google Inc, NYC

(Summer 2011)

- Worked with the team managing reliability infrastructure of global computing clusters.
- Constructed simple tools to collect and analyze statistical information from clusters.

## Software Engineering Intern, Google Inc, Mountain View, CA

(Summer 2010)

• Worked on a mobile e-mail client prototype.

## Lab Teaching Assistant, Computer Science Dept., UW-Madison

(Fall 2009)

- Monitored undergraduate students for a introductory java course.
- Worked with a team to create and handle programming assignments.

#### Education

#### University of Wisconsin-Madison

(Sep 2009 - Dec 2016)

Ph.D. in Computer Science, Dec 2016, Thesis: Application Crash Consistency.

M.S. in Computer Science, May 2011, GPA: 3.875/4.0

Advisors: Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau

## College of Engineering, Guindy, Anna University, India

(May 2005 - May 2009)

B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering

CGPA: 9.1/10.0

### **Selected Publications**

Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai, Ramnatthan Alagappan, Lanyue Lu, Vijay Chidambaram, Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau, "Application Crash Consistency and Performance with CCFS", FAST 2017 (Best paper award), TOS Sep 2017.

Lanyue Lu, Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai, Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau, "WiscKey: Separating Keys from Values in SSD-conscious Storage", FAST 2016, TOS March 2017.

Ramnatthan Alagappan, Aishwarya Ganesan, Yuvraj Patel, Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai, Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau, "Correlated Crash Vulnerabilities", OSDI 2016.

Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai, Vijay Chidambaram, Ramnatthan Alagappan, Samer Al-Kiswany, Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau, "Crash Consistency", CACM October 2015, ACM Queue July 2015.

Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai, Vijay Chidambaram, Ramnatthan Alagappan, Samer Al-Kiswany, Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau, "All File Systems Are Not Created Equal: On the Complexity of Crafting Crash-Consistent Applications", OSDI 2014.

Vijay Chidambaram, Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai, Andrea C. Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi H. Arpaci-Dusseau, "Optimistic Crash Consistency", SOSP 2013.

 $\textbf{Full list of publications on Google Scholar:} \ \ \texttt{https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=pUXUqXMAAAAJ}$